The only way to make money in trading
without having to look at the market
every single hour before opens and
closes is by simply swing trading. Swing
trading allows you to understand the
bigger picture of the market and this
way you are able to capitalize off of
bigger moves. There's a better
alternative to trading other than just
watching [music] it when it opens,
watching it when it closes, and having
to follow the daily direction of the
market. Swing trading is the best
single-handed way in order for you to
maximize the [music] most amount of
money from the markets. You can look at,
for example, this trade where it made me
$414,000 [music]
in 4 days. This is a semi swing trade
and I'm going to break down in this
video exactly how I did that and I'm
also going to be breaking down this
trade where I made about 250 to 260,000
dollars where I held for a little bit
over a week. [music] Swing trading is
the perfect way to trade if you have a
9:00 to 5:00 job, if you're busy with
school, because you enter a position and
you let the direction of the market for
the entire week make you profits while
you simply lay back and let the market
continue trading with the friend that
you're doing. So, with that being said,
let's get right into it. Now, for those
that might not know, let me give you a
little bit of context on what swing
trading is. So, swing trading is
actually the safest way to trade. Might
take a little bit of longer for the
markets to play out. There's some pros
and cons, but let me give you the full
framework of it. Swing trading is where
you're trading with the higher time
frames. The reason why it is safer is
because the higher time frames are very
predictable because it takes a very long
time for certain market structure to be
created. For example, let's say you're
going to build a concrete block and you
were to give it 30 days to dry, it's
going to be a lot stronger compared to a
concrete block that you give it 24 hours
to dry. So, every single candlestick
that is performed on the higher time
frames for swing trading take a lot more
time for it to be created. [music] So,
it's going to be a lot more respected
compared to the lower time frames where
things happen very fast. That is not as
concrete, it's not as strong, it's not
as respected. So, the higher time frames
are very predictable because the market
moves in patterns [music] and these
patterns take very long for them to
create themselves. So, they're very
predictable. It just simply requires
patience. [music] So, when you're
trading with swing trading, you're
holding for longer because the moves are
bigger and you're having safer trades
because there are a lot more
predictable. So, you are you're able to
not only be able to risk more on
positions because they're less risky and
you're able to maximize more profits
without you having to overexpose
yourself. The only con when it comes to
swing trading is you will need some
patience. But, as time goes on, this
becomes inevitable and normal in
trading. Now, understanding that there's
three popular ways to trade. You have
scalping, day trading, and the swing
trade. Scalping is anywhere a trade that
can take anywhere from 30 minutes to
about 1 hour where you're really holding
a position for a very quick move. You're
not targeting trades that are going with
the higher time frames. You're just
trading the move for that specific
session. So, if you're trading market
open, you just want to catch the impulse
move from when the market opens or right
before the market closes, you just want
to catch that impulse move. This
requires a lot more trades because
you're just trading these sporadic moves
up or down and you could be in and out
of a position probably two to three
times every single day, which you're
going to have a much more lower win
rates and you're going to have a lot
more quantity amount of trades. So, this
is where I don't personally like trading
just because it is a it's very stressful
having to predict and change the bias of
the move every single day. But, traders
that have a sense of
urgency to trade every single day like
trading it, but it's very stressful
because you have to be in front of the
markets for many hours at a time and
constantly changing your bias in the
market. Day trading is pretty much the
perfect medium in between scalping and
swing trading. It's where you're trading
a direction for the entire day or for
the next day market open, market close.
So, for example, let's say market opens
in New York session, you anticipate for
moves to happen to the upside, you're
going to continue to trade for the
upside for the duration of that session.
Could be 5, 6, 7, 8 hours typically is
what a day trade last, or you can take a
trade that will last overnight, which is
also considered a day trade/intraday
trade, where you're holding it during
the duration of the next day. Now, this
style of trading, you're not really
taking that many amount of trades. You
can probably take one to two trades in a
day max, but you're not changing your
biased and you're not looking for
impulse moves. In scalp trading, you're
looking for a big impulse move just to
catch that move and then get out. You
don't care what the overall direction
really comes down to because you just
want a quick move to get in and out of
the market. Day trading, you are taking
a little bit of anticipation to the
higher time frames, but also combining a
bit of the scalping with the
impulsiveness, because you want to get
out of the position that very same day
or that next day. In scalping, you want
to get out within the hour. Day trading,
you want to get out within the same day
or the next day. And the win rate for
day trading can typically be anywhere
from 50 to 55%, which is very healthy,
and you're in the middle of a quality
and quantity, simply because you're
looking to take a trade every single
day, depending on the session and
depending on the direction of that
session. Now, swing trading is the
godfather of all of these trades. It
does require a bit more patience,
[music]
and it simply comes down to trading with
the trend, purely. If you are swing
trading, you want to anticipate a
position that can continue to go in a
direction for weeks at a time. And it's
very easy to scale in positions that you
can anticipate if it's going to continue
going up for the next two to three
weeks. So, once you're an experienced
trader, like myself, you can understand
how to day trade and scalp on a swing
trading move. Because if you can
anticipate that the trade is going to
continue going up for the next two to
three weeks, you can find these smaller
positions inside of that bigger
position, where then you capitalize off
of a swing trade, a day trade, and a
scalp position. Swing trades really come
down to maybe one to two trades a week,
if that. And you don't care how long it
takes for it to get to your take profit.
Typically, what it should last is
anywhere from
4 to about 8 9 days, and you can make
three to four, even five times what any
day trade and any scalp trade could
take.
>> [music]
>> The reason for this is because you need
to wait for those weekly candlesticks to
close. Those weekly candlesticks take
about 5 days to close, or at least
trading days.
>> [music]
>> And those candlesticks opening and
closing dictate the direction of the
following [music] week. So, for example,
let's say you're looking to buy on the
weekly time frame based off of the trend
of a swing trade, and it closes bullish
in that direction. If next week it
closed bullish and you're still looking
for more buys, why would you want to cut
your winning position short? It's only
indicating that it can continue to go in
that direction. You're simply going to
continue to hold. Now, what an
experienced trader like myself and many
members of my academy do is we find day
trades within that swing trade position,
[music] and then we capitalize off of
that every step of the way. It's a bit
riskier because you're overexposing
yourself to an additional risk by
entering another trade, but if you have
the bigger swing trade to hedge that day
trade, you're really not putting
anything at risk. If you're in profit
way down here and [music] you're adding
an extra position up here, even if that
day trade loses for whatever reason,
that swing trade can make back that
loss, and you don't have anything at
risk.
>> [music]
>> So, the beauty of understanding how to
swing trade is the godfather, like I
mentioned, of all of these time frames
>> [music]
>> and these different trading styles
because regardless of what happens on
the lower time frames, if you can
predict the direction of the higher time
frames, this [music] is obviously far
greater, and it is a lot less stressful.
The main reason why I am a swing trader
and why I was able to actually
learn this strategy is because I had a
job when I learned how to trade, and I
didn't have the availability to be in
front of the market at market open or
even on scalping. So, I was forced to
understand and learn trading this way.
And I'm very grateful for it because
now, longer term, it's helped me
understand the direction of the entire
market. So, swing trading you can have a
win rate anywhere from
60 to 65% but the risk to reward is by
far the greatest and you're able to have
that recovery from any losses that you
can have. You make back losses far
easier because your profits are far
larger. Now, I will warn you, swing
trading has a bit of a bittersweet taste
to it simply because of one thing,
patience. Does not matter any type of
human that you are. When you are having
an opportunity to click a buy and a sell
button 24/5 the entire week, temptation
will kick in. Doesn't matter how
experienced [music] you are, how much
patience you have, that temptation of
clicking that buy and sell button is
always in the back of your head. It's
like if you have a little devil here on
your shoulder constantly telling you to
execute a trade. And swing trading will
require the most amount of patience
because there can be times where you're
looking at the markets for a duration of
4 days. So, hopping in and out of the
market, looking at it and analyzing for
20 to 30 minutes, and not entering a
position. You might miss out on
opportunities, you might miss out on
these smaller moves, and that can really
affect your psychological aspect [music]
of trading because you're constantly
battling on entering a position or not
[music] because it you have to wait for
the perfect trade that can continue to
go in that direction for the duration of
a week [music] or 2 weeks. So, it's
great as soon as you enter a good
position because you're making money
week after week without having to do
absolutely [music] nothing, but it is
very, very difficult at times to do
nothing. When you're not entering a
position and when you're in a position,
us as human, we are human at the end of
the day, we will fall into temptation,
any type of temptation. It's almost like
if you love sweets and there's a jar
full of candy and they tell you, "Hey,
you can't have any candy for 4 days."
And the jar of candy is following you
everywhere for 4 days. You know, it
might You know, you might put your hand
in the cookie jar once and take a bit of
that sweet. Trading is no different than
that. The market is available 24/5 for
you to enter a position, and you have to
be very patient for when it's the right
time for you to enter that position.
Before you enter it, and once you're in
that position, you need to let that
winning trade run. I know it's very
difficult at times to see a winning
position even come back into a little
bit of a retracement, and miss out on
profits that you had at that
time. But, if you're swing trading, you
need to understand that the market will
create these retracements
>> [music]
>> in order for the market to continue
going to the upside. From the moment you
enter, it's not going to be a ginormous
candlestick
>> [music]
>> to go straight to your take profit. It
needs to create structure to go to that
take profit. So, that will consist
[music] of highs and lows to get to the
point where you're supposed to be. And
you need to be able to have the stomach
[music] and the patience for you to be
able to weather that storm. And that is
what crushes traders in swing trading.
People can predict the direction for the
next 2 weeks, and that's all easy. But,
what isn't that easy is being patient
letting for that trade to go all the way
[music] to your take profit. So, if I
were to have the main con of swing
trading or just trading in general will
be patience. Waiting for that right
setup, and letting that setup play out.
Biggest battle you will face regardless
of what level you are in in trading, and
once you master that is where everything
changes. Now, enough with the talking,
let me actually go into the charts and
give you a real-life example of a trade
that I entered. This is GBP/NZD that
made me a quarter million dollars. Now,
I know that might seem like a lot, and
it is a lot of money, but you need to
understand that I also risked a lot in
order for me to make that. I risked
about 80 to 90,000 dollars on this exact
same position. That's why I was able to
make this amount of money. So, don't
think that I risked $1,000 or $2,000 to
make a quarter million dollars. No. I
put a lot of money at risk to make this
money. But, the beauty of this trade is
I was able to predict it for the
duration of 2 to 3 weeks. So, the beauty
of GBP/NZD is I was predicting the
retracement of this trade. So, I'm about
to get very technical on this trade. So,
bear with me. If you're driving, stop
driving. Shouldn't be watching a video
if you're driving. But, just saying that
just in case you don't know. If you're
at a coffee shop, put the volume up, put
your headphones on. If you're at work,
take a break. Pay attention to this
because this can be completely changed
in your entire trading by understanding
how the market moves. So,
when it comes to understanding any swing
trade, the most important thing that you
need to understand is the trend. Where
is the trend headed in that position?
For example, this trade
in this market that I'm drawing up here,
it's very obvious that this market is
clearly heading to the downside. We all
know the lower highs and the lower lows
of the market. This is a lower high.
This is a lower low. Whenever a market
has a lower low, we anticipate for the
trade to have a lower high. On this
lower high, we anticipate for it to have
a new lower low. That's simply how the
market moves. That is market structure.
Let's imagine this as if it were to be a
staircase going to the downside. In
order for you to go from one staircase
to the next one, you have to step here.
And then after you step here, you step
here, and you step here. You need to go
through every single one of these steps
in order for you to get to the next
step. Can you skip a step? Can you go
from this step to this step? Yes, but
you will probably fall and break your
ankle. I'm sure we've all been there.
Except the breaking the ankle.
Trading is no different. In order for
you to be able to predict these swing
legs to the downside, you need to have
these retracements that you anticipate
in order for this move to go to the
downside. Now, this trade in specific,
GBP/NZD, I predicted the low of this
leg. So, as you can tell here, this
market was very beautifully creating
higher highs and higher lows, higher
highs, shifted structure, and then it
created a lower low. So, this market was
very predictable because we created a
massive push to the downside. So, we
were clearly bullish at one point. This
was the higher high in this market right
here. After we created this higher high,
we had this higher low. After this
higher low, we shifted the structure.
So, now this became the new lower low,
and then this became the lower high.
What happens after we have a lower low
move? In order for us to continue to go
to the downside, we need to predict a
lower high to then continue going to the
downside. There's no way that this
market could just continue freefalling
for the entirety of the move. No, it
needs to create these retracements right
here in order for it to go to the
downside. So, me understanding this
direction of the markets on the higher
time frames, I then go looked for
entries on the lower time frame. So, I
have a swing trade analysis, but then I
can go take an intraday entry. That's
exactly what this trade consisted of. My
swing trade analysis was very
predictable.
After this move, had this massive push
to the downside, we got near the support
level that every single time we're
above, we clearly reject up, we clearly
reject up, and here we were clearly
going to reject up. When I go down to
the daily time frame, daily time frame
made it as clear as possible that we're
going to have that leg for the lower
high to have the push to the upside. So,
we know that on the weekly time frame,
this is the big leg that we're
anticipating for this move to come up
and then continue go to the downside.
Now, on the daily time frame, as you can
see here, this created a lower low,
lower high, lower low, lower high, lower
low, lower high, lower low. And then we
had a shift. So, now we went from
creating lower highs and lower lows to
higher highs and higher lows. If I were
to bring this market structure right
here,
you can very much see lower high, lower
low, lower high, lower low, lower high,
lower low, and then we shifted to the
upside. It's almost as if we were to be
in a bearish channel to the downside,
and then we shifted to having a bullish
channel to the upside. This is the
beauty of understanding how to read
market structure. The lower time frames,
or the next lower time frame, which is
the daily versus the weekly, is giving
me the indication that it is shifting
right here and creating moves to the
upside to have that retracement for the
higher time frame. You need to remember
the higher time frame was like this.
It was consolidating, and then we had
the push to the downside. Now, this is
indicating to me that it's ready to have
this retracement. This is exactly how it
looks like. So, it's ready to have this
retracement to this area, so then it can
have the push to the downside. So, I'm
taking a intraday  intra swing
position for this retracement here, so
then we can enter the continuation sell
to the downside. All of this because I
can understand how to read the higher
time frames.
So, what I do on GBP NZD, I can identify
that we are indeed heading to the
upside, and I can see that we have not
only the bullish structure, but we also
have resistance.
>> [music]
>> We also have supports. When I go more to
the left, we have supports, we have
resistance, we have resistance,
resistance,
>> [music]
>> and resistance. Clearly, whenever we're
below these points, we're heading down.
Whenever we're above it, we're very much
going up. Whenever we're above, we head
up. Whenever we're below, we head down.
Whenever we're below, we head down.
[music] Whenever we're above,
we should head up, right? This isn't
rocket science. All I'm doing is
understanding the higher time frames
need that bigger retracement. The next
lower time frame [music] is indicating
to me that it's having that shift to
give it that retracement, and then we're
above a massive area whenever we're
below we head down and we're we're above
we head up. This is not even related
remotely to how my strategy works. This
is just simple understanding of what the
market is telling me right now. This is
not my exact strategy. This is not a
concept. This is not a
SMC, ICT, whatever. This is literally
just understanding what the market is
presenting. Picture this as if it were
to be
>> [music]
>> the English language of the ABCs. This
is literally the letters, the ABCs of
the market. I'm just reading the
letters. Now, how I put those letters
together and how I make my own words is
where my strategy comes in, how I enter,
so on and so forth. This is just the
basics, and 90% [music] of the people
can't do this correct. That's why they
are not successful.
Because they can't understand the
overall direction of the market. Now,
after that, price is above my EMA. After
it's being above the EMA, I then look
for entries on the lower time frames,
and that's where I I entered this
position around this zone right here. My
stop loss is below the very strong level
of support or resistance because
clearly, if we're going to go hit this
position and we're going to make it to
this area, we're going to be below it.
What happens if we get below this
resistance? We should technically then
head to the downside. So, I'm always
going to put my stop loss at an area
where if it gets hit, I am entirely
wrong. That is the most important thing.
I can't tell you how many traders trades
I review and they're putting the stop
loss at around 20 pips, 25 pips, 30 pips
for no specific for literally no reason.
They don't have an explanation. They're
like, "Oh, I just like the number 27."
What does your number 27 have to do with
the market? Nothing. You need to put
your stop loss at an area where it has
some significance, and [music] if it
gets hit, you're entirely wrong. That's
what the point of the stop loss is. One
reason of the stop loss
is to obviously [music] cut your losses
and stop you out where you're
comfortable with your risk. And two, if
the market heads to that area, you're
entirely wrong in the direction. I can't
stress how many people put their stop
losses just based off of where they
think they should put it and have no
understanding of where [music] it should
actually go based off of what the market
is telling them. This stop loss just
logically makes sense. It's below this
zone because if the market goes below
this zone, what happens? It should
continue to go below zone. So that means
I'm entirely wrong in the direction of
this trade. Whenever I get stopped out
of a position, 70% of the time, 80% of
the time, the market goes in the
complete opposite direction like for
weeks at a time. So where I analyzed the
direction of the trade, I was wrong.
Right? So this position right here, I
was basically buying into that weekly
area of interest. Now the beauty of this
trade is that I am anticipating this
trade to continue to go into the
downside. Right? So let's take a step
back. I'm buying this position to the
weekly area [music] of interest where we
can potentially continue to go to the
downside. Remember, what I'm
anticipating from this trade [music] is
for this weekly time frame to have a
lower low leg, have a lower high leg,
and then continue going to the downside.
So I'm taking an intraday trade on this
retracement before it continues to go to
the downside. So what I want to do is
I'm placing my take profit at a weekly
area. If I look left based off of this
market, clearly same exact It's It's
literally the exact same concept as
highs. This zone, whenever we're below,
we head down. Whenever we're below, we
head down. Whenever we're above, we head
up. Whenever we're above, we head up. So
for me, I'm buying into this area
because I expect for the weekly time
frame to get to this zone and then
continue to go to the downside. Now,
obviously, I enter my position entering
[music] it to that weekly zone, and then
here is where the trade ends up going
all the way to our take profit. Round
psychological level, 2300, and we broke
above that, which is great.
The beauty of swing trading is that you
can anticipate these bigger moves, and I
could have maximized and gotten a 1:2,
1:3, 1:4, but I was content with my
position being at a 1:2 because I
understood logically that the weekly
timeframe should have stopped at this
area and then continued to go to the
downside. But, if I would have followed
my rules, which is what I explained to
you guys earlier, waiting for that
weekly candlestick to close, which is
this candlestick here, I would have
closed it at the top here for a little
extra half a percent near an extra
percent on the position. At the time, I
just wanted to close the position,
didn't need to hold any further, and I
made that decision. But, this is the
beauty of sticking to those swing
trading analysis and overall directions
of the market. Now, obviously, you fast
forward a couple of weeks, and then this
market ended up indeed having a reaction
from this area slightly after it had the
push to the upside. So, all of this is
by understanding the direction of the
market. When the market is heading down,
you understand it needs to have a little
bit of a retracement before it continue
to go down to the downside. And in this
position, obviously, continued to go to
the downside, rejecting this resistance
from this point here. So, me entering
this position, I bought perfectly into
this resistance, and then from this
resistance, we then had a push to the
downside, and I did not enter this
position here. I placed a
risk-to-reward, I just fell asleep and
missed out on this position. That's part
of the process as well. When you're
swing trading, you can predict the
direction, but sometimes life happens.
You have to go to work. My case, I was
just asleep. I was tired. [music]
I think I was traveling and I wasn't
able to be awake to enter this position.
And I missed out on that trade. It is
what it is. It's part of the process.
But, all of this is by understanding the
direction of the markets. It is the most
important thing and the backbone of
every single trade, and truthfully,
should be of every trade. If scalpers,
in my opinion,
would understand how to use the higher
time [music] frames with them, they
would be very powerful. But, they're so
focused on the 1-minute time frame,
5-minute time frame, and they they don't
understand that it only takes 5 minutes
for a candlestick to close. Which one do
you think is more powerful? The
candlestick that takes 5 minutes to
close or the one that takes 5 days?
Obviously, the one that takes 5 days
will be a lot more respected. And I
think a lot of people really overlook
swing trading because it is the most
powerful for people that have 9-5s, for
people that go to school, and genuinely
have a busy schedule. Because if you can
throw in that position, I entered it and
I waited 5, 6, 7 days for it to get to
my take profit, and I could have held it
for another 5, 6, 7 days and doing
absolutely nothing, it could have
continuously made me money. I don't have
the stress of looking at the charts
every single day to make a decision. I
don't have to reanalyze the market for
whatever reason, and I don't have to
second-guess my overall direction
because I'm trading with the higher time
frames. I'm not scared that it's going
to change direction if a new session
comes in with a lot of volatility and
everything goes backwards. Not at all.
The beauty of this is I learned this
when I was working at Dunkin' Donuts. I
was working I was a 7:00 to 2:00, so
that was my schedule. 7:00 in the
morning, 6:00 in the morning till 2:00,
3:00 in the afternoon. So, I would do my
analysis on Sunday, enter the position
before I would go into work, and the
duration of the day that I am at work,
the trade is going in the direction that
I analyzed for the duration of that
week. So, I can be at work stress-free,
open my phone for 30 seconds, see how
it's doing it, put it back in my pocket
just because I wanted to see how the
position was doing. And the most
successful students inside of my academy
are the ones that are actually devoting
the least amount of time to looking at
the markets during the duration of the
week. If you understand how to identify
the direction of the market every single
Sunday before the market opens, where
you have literally no option but to just
analyze the market and not enter a
trade, you can make an analysis that is
entirely s- entirely neutrally based
because you're not making analysis to
enter a trade. You're making an analysis
to understand the direction of the
market. And your psychological battle is
not even there because you're just
analyzing for a trade that you could
take for the duration of the week, not
for a trade you could take that very
second. That's the beauty of swing
trading because when you're scalping or
day trading, you make an analysis that
very moment when the market is live and
you almost see things you shouldn't be
seeing because you want to enter
position right there, right that second.
With swing trading, that's not the case.
You do an analysis when the market is
closed and you do it for what is
actually there. And you can make a
analysis with a cold mindset and really
read the market for what it is. So, it's
very powerful, very predictable, and
this is what I do every single Sunday
with my students. I review the trade
setups on what they did the week before,
make sure they're doing their analysis
right. I get on calls with them and I
give them the exact markets that I am
interested in trading for that week and
we discuss what is the correct thing to
do, what is the incorrect [music] thing
to do, where should we place our take
profits, where should we place our stop
losses. And yes, we do this every single
Sunday. If you want to join my private
community where I get to review your
trades and you get to get these analyses
before the market even happens every
single Sunday with me live, DM me the
word Sunday Swings. I'll even link in
the description down below of my
personal Instagram. Just DM me the word
Sunday Swings and we'll have a chat
about it and see what markets are
available for that current week and what
opportunities are presenting themselves.
And we get a deep understanding of why
we should be entering a trade in this
direction rather than this direction.
Because the most important thing when it
comes to swing trading is removing all
of the trades that don't make sense.
There's 75 different currency pairs that
you can enter a position on and the goal
isn't to enter every single one of those
positions. It's to hash out the ones
that aren't clean and focus on the ones
that are giving you the best possible
opportunity. I do that every single
Sunday with my students. So, just DM me
the word Sunday Swings and we'll have a
chat about it so you can potentially be
parts of my academy. But, with that
being said, I hope you guys enjoyed this
video. Make sure to pay attention to
that market structure. It's the most
important thing to predicting the
overall direction of the trend. If you
guys like this video, hit that like, hit
that thumbs up. Make sure to subscribe
and I'll see you guys in the next video.
Take care, guys.